The SCOAN Sunday Service
Hallelujah!
You may be seated. Thank you.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Don't let this appearance take you off.
Let us celebrate the Being in my word today -
the Life, Jesus Christ.
Hallelujah!
Well.
Let us rise up and pray.
Viewers all over the world, let us pray.
We want to be one. If we are not one, we cannot move that mountain.
Now, we are going into His presence in a mighty way.
You must make sure your heart is not fearful.
You must make sure your heart does not comdemn you.
You must make sure your heart is in perfect fellowship with His living Word.
Be conscious that you are welcome.
Tell your neighbour, "Be conscious that you are welcome".
I can't hear you.
[Be conscious that you are welcome.]
Yes.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
That root that keeps unforgiveness alive in you - be terminated, in the name of Jesus!
That root that keeps anger, bitterness, envy, jealousy, pain of the past -
be terminated, in the name of Jesus!
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Yes.
You need a free spirit to follow Him.
I have decided to follow Jesus
No turning back
The SCOAN Sunday Service
You need a free spirit to follow Him.
The Spirit of God cannot share with a heart full of unforgiveness, anger, bitterness,
pain of the past, bad feelings towards others.
That root that keeps pain of the past alive in you - be terminated, in the name of Jesus!
Be terminated, in the name of Jesus!
You know those areas in your life.
You know those against whom you are holding grudges.
Unforgiveness.
It is not always easy to forgive but we that are Christ's followers must follow His example.
Are you there?
It is not always easy to forgive the pain of the past
but we that are Christ's followers must follow His example.
If Christ could forgive the people who were killing Him,
we can certainly find a way to forgive those who hurt us.
When we cannot forgive, we are hurting ourselves more than anyone;
we are destroying ourselves more than anyone.
Tell your neighbour, "When you cannot forgive, you are destroying yourself,
you are hurting yourself more than anyone".
Tell your neighbour again.
[When you cannot forgive, you are destroying yourself more than anyone.]
Yes. You say, "Oh, that person embarrassed me! He insulted me!"
and you are holding that pain.
When you cannot forgive, you are hurting yourself,
you are destroying yourself and your future.
Any step you take, you take it into darkness, when you cannot forgive -
whether you are right or wrong.
More than anyone.
Nursing a grudge damages our heart.
Tell your neighbour, "Nursing a grudge damages our heart".
I can't hear you.
[Nursing a grudge damages our heart.]
Nursing bitterness, unforgiveness, anger, pain of the past - whether you are right or wrong -
damages your heart.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Can you see?
Here you are.
In Your presence
I am content
In Your presence there is light
Expressions of Your love
Revelations of Your power and might
In Your presence I can bring
A love song offering
I'm in the presence of my King
Listen to that.
A step towards His presence - you are moving to His presence,
you want to move to God.
Your heart must be free from condemnation.
Make sure your heart is not fearful, does not condemn you,
is in perfect fellowship with His living Word.
Be conscious that you are welcome.
"Yes, I'm welcome."
Hallowed be
Hallowed be Your name
Lord and majesty
Divine authority
Hallowed be Your name
That is it. Hallowed be Your name.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Your heart must not be fearful.
Are you sure you are conscious that you are welcome?
When your heart is jumping up and down, the pain of the past?
Are you sure you are here?
[Yes!]
I'm not talking to you, I'm talking to your heart.
He is Lord
Amen
He has risen from the dead
And He is Lord
Every knee shall bow
Every tongue confess
That Jesus Christ is Lord
It's not too late.
You can reconcile your account now.
In Jesus Christ's name!
[Amen!]
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Ask your neighbour, "Are you sure that you are welcome?"
[Are you sure that you are welcome?]
Are you conscious that you are welcome?
[Are you conscious that you are welcome?]
You may be seated.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Hallelujah.
Let God's Word abide in us.
We take our reading from the Book of 1. Corinthians 2:13-14.
Take your time.
And the Book of Philippians 1:27.
And also the Book of John 15:7.
And the Book of James 1:21.
And the last reading will be 1 John 3:20.
Let me just take that first book
and I will leave the rest for you to read after the message.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
1 Corinthians 2.
"And so it was with me, brothers and sisters.
When I came to you, I did not come with eloquence or human wisdom
as I proclaimed to you the testimony about God."
What is the testimony about God?
That is what I proclaimed to you.
"For I resolved to know nothing while I was with you except Jesus Christ and Him crucified.
I came to you in weakness with great fear and trembling."
Verse 4.
"My message and my preaching were not with wise and persuasive words
but with a demonstration of the Spirit's power
so that your faith might not rest on human wisdom, but on God's power."
That last verse - read it with me again - which is 5.
"so that your faith might not rest on human wisdom, but on God's power."
But today, our faith rests on human wisdom.
In the ministry of apostles - the ministry of Christ Jesus,
the spirit of man is the fountain of faith.
But today, our faith rests on human wisdom.
That is why we have not been seeing Jesus on the scene.
When we say, "Jesus Christ", where is Jesus Christ?
When you say, "Jesus Christ", you are to bring Jesus Christ to the scene.
Today, our faith rests on human wisdom.
Like I have given you - when you take your reading - the Book of Phillipians 1:27
and the Book of John 8:31 - you will get it clear.
And the Book of James 1:21.
And the last reading which is 1 John 3:20.
You have more.
Abide in the Word of God.
When you look around today, you will see that our schools, colleges, technical institutions
are for the moulding of the mind.
What do I mean by mind? - I mean, intellectual capacity.
This is what we are building.
We can see all over the world intellectual capacity.
All the knowledge we have has come through the senses.
And you will agree with me that there is nothing creative in the senses.
That is, there is nothing original.
Senses is about 'letter'. Where does the letter come from?
It is about 'letter' - "Jesus Christ".
This is why today, there is nothing original in reading the Bible without the help of the Holy Spirit.
Let me take the Bible to show you what I'm talking about.
See.
If I take the Bible because of my knowledge of the senses -
well educated or author - and I take it and read it -
Jesus this, Jesus that -
there is nothing original in reading the Bible without the help of the Holy Spirit.
There is nothing creative, there is nothing original in the letter.
It is 'letter'.
The Bible without the help of the Holy Spirit is 'letter'.
The Bible without the help of the Holy Spirit is mere 'letter'.
You can only teach it, preach it but to bring Jesus to the scene,
or to bring the Spirit of God into our heart - no.
This is why there is a cycle today.
We read the Bible without the help of the Holy Ghost.
How little we know about building our spirit.
That is why we read the Bible without the help of the Holy Ghost.
Unless today's church realises that the spirit of man is the fountain of faith,
that is when God - the Holy Spirit will be involved in our affairs -
the affair of the church and our life.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
I take it again.
Unless today's church realises that the spirit of man is the fountain of faith,
that is when God - the Holy Spirit will be involved in our affairs.
If not, we are carrying 'letter', history.
That is why anyone can go to the bookshop and obtain a Bible
without being a Christian, without being a believer.
Just give money, they will give you a Bible.
When you go to many occult organisations today, you will see them using the same Bible
because it is a 'letter' without the Holy Ghost.
Without the Holy Ghost, it is a 'letter'.
Committing the Word to memory is valuable but does not do it -
I mean, does not bring Jesus to the scene, does not bring God's Spirit into our heart.
Committing the Word to memory - I mean, learning the history of the books of the Bible is valuable -
you can learn the history of the books of the Bible and become a lecturer, teacher, preacher;
it is valuable but does not do it - does not bring Jesus to the scene,
does not bring God's Spirit into our heart.
Learning the Hebrew or Greek words is valuable
but will not do it.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Only one thing
will do it:
Our doing the Word, living it in our daily life, practicing it, trusting in it, acting on it -
that is our secret.
Only one thing will do it:
Our doing the Word,
practicing it, living it in our daily life,
acting on it- that is our secret.
The just shall live by faith.
Faith has given birth to all the great achievements of man.
Feeding on the Word is feeding on God's wisdom.
Feeding on the Word is feeding on God's ability.
Feeding on the Word is feeding on God's very life.
Feeding on the Word - for you to know how important...
As you feed on the Word, it cultivates, strengthens, builds faith into you, builds God's ability into you,
builds your spirit up, builds into you every attractive thing that you see in the life of Jesus.
Trust and obey
For there's no other way
To be happy in Jesus
Than to trust and obey
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Controlling your meditation while reading the Bible
gives ability to control your conduct and your speech.
Yielding your heart to the Word of God makes the Word a reality.
When you yield your heart to the Word of God, it makes the Word of God a reality.
When the Word becomes a reality, you become God-minded and Word-minded.
When you become God-minded and Word-minded, in the morning,
your spirit unconsciously goes to Him for guidance and wisdom for the day.
Unconsciously.
You will just wake up and find yourself...
Your spirit unconsciously goes to Him for guidance and wisdom for the day
when you become God-minded and Word-minded.
Tell your neighbour, "When you become God-minded and Word-minded,
your spirit unconsciously goes to God for guidance and wisdom for the day.
It is not an issue of "I have not prayed". How do you know you have not prayed?
It is a thing of the spirit.
"Wait for me, I want to pray."
Ah! Your prayer has become your job.
It is spiritual.
"Wait for me, I want to pray. Please tell him I'm praying."
"Hm, I'm praying. When you were calling me, I was praying."
It is becoming your job; not the Spirit's job.
When we don't know how to pray, the Spirit is helping our weakness.
When you become God-minded and Word-minded, in the morning,
your spirit unconsciously goes to God for guidance and wisdom for the day.
In the morning
Early in the morning
I will rise and praise the Lord
In the morning
Early in the morning
I will rise and praise the Lord
Good morning Jesus
Good morning Lord
I know You come from Heaven above
The Holy Spirit is on the throne
Good morning Jesus
Good morning Lord
I will enter His gates
With thanksgiving in my heart
I will enter His courts with praise
I will say this is the day that the Lord has made
I will rejoice for He has made me glad
He has made me glad
I am so glad
I will rejoice for He has made me glad
He has made me glad
I am so glad
I will rejoice for He has made me glad
When you feed on the Word, it makes your way plain before you.
You say, "Ah, what will I do this morning? I don't know what to do!"
"I don't know whether that business will be right."
"I don't know whether that man will attend to me."
"Ah, I'm worried. I don't know. Let me go."
When you feed on the Word, it makes your way plain before you.
Tell your neighbour.
[When you feed on the Word, it makes your way plain before you.]
I can't hear you.
You just find that in the morning, you start laughing.
People say, "Why are you laughing?"
"Because I'm happy!
Things may look very rough on the outside but on the inside, I'm happy!"
Because you are feeding on the Word.
When you feed on the Word, it makes your way plain before you.
When you feed on the Word, the Word becomes a reality.
In a crisis situation such as sickness, disease, hardship, poverty, you will not be afraid
because satan, the cause of crisis, has been defeated.
When you feed on the Word of God, the Word becomes a reality.
In a crisis situation such as sickness, disease, hardship, poverty, setback...you will not be afraid
because satan, the cause of crisis, has been defeated
and Jesus gave you the power of attorney to use His name.
Look, you need to know! This Bible is demanding!
As you feed on the Word, you dominate circumstances around you - live above them.
The Bible says, "Cheer up! I have overcome!"
It is true!
You just need to feed on the Word of God.
If that Word finds its way, if that Word of God finds its place in your heart,
by its very nature, it changes you automatically.
When you are changed, you will be called to act, to serve.
You will engage yourself in His projects - that is, God's projects.
There are God's projects.
The projects you are engaging yourself in -
there are God's projects and there are people's projects.
When you are called to serve, you engage in His projects.
When you engage in His projects, you begin to know God's opinion about yourself and others.
You know Jesus loves you.
How do you know when you do not belong to Him?
You can only belong to Jesus by being filled by His Spirit.
Are you filled by God's Spirit?
When you are filled by God's Spirit, you are emptied of your own.
You cannot be full of God's Spirit and also still of yourself.
Take more of me, give me more of You.
To belong to Jesus, you must be filled by His Spirit and emptied of your own.
Let's worship Him.
You raise me up
You raise me up so I can stand on mountains
You raise me up to walk on stormy seas
I am strong when I am on Your shoulders
You raise me up to more than I can be
You raise me up so I can stand on mountains
You raise me up to walk on stormy seas
I am strong when I am on Your shoulders
You raise me up to more than I can be
When I am down and oh my soul so weary
When troubles come and my heart burdens me
Then I am still and wait here in the silence
Until You come and sit a while with me
You raise me up so I can stand on mountains
You raise me up to walk on stormy seas
I am strong when I am on Your shoulders
You raise me up to more than I can be
You raise me up so I can stand on mountains
You raise me up to walk on stormy seas
I am strong when I am on Your shoulders
You raise me up to more than I can be
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Now, the question - what is the state of your heart?
Because this is what we are talking about. You can't go anywhere without this heart.
Christianity lies in the heart. What is the state of your heart?
The Holy Spirit cannot share with a heart full of unforgiveness, bitterness, anger, pain of the past,
bad feelings towards neighbours, bad feelings towards others.
What is the state of your heart?
So we are singing and dancing.
That is the question for you to answer now.
Ask yourself - what is the state of my heart?
We know it is not always easy to forgive.
We that are Christ's followers must live by His example.
If Christ could forgive the people who were killing Him -
"Father, forgive them", including you and I, "they don't know what they are doing" -
who is your Father, we can certainly find a way to forgive those who hurt us
because when you cannot forgive, the hurt on you is more than on anyone,
the destruction, failure, nightmare on you is more than on anyone - if you cannot forgive.
Tell your neighbour.
When we cannot forgive, the hurt on us is more than on anyone,
the destruction on us is more than on anyone,
the failure on us is more than on anyone,
the nightmare on us is more than on anyone.
Who needs forgiveness?
When you cannot forgive and you are saying, "I'm right, I'm just, I'm justified" -
you say, "You are right", they insulted you -
that is what you are holding against your neighbour...
If you cannot forgive, the hurt, destruction, failure, nightmare on you is more than on anyone.
This is what we are facing today.
This is what churches are facing today.
Unforgiveness is the burden we have.
"That man is not good", "That woman is not good", "That church is not good" -
as if you are the founder and you are God.
Because of that, you hold a grudge.
That "that man is not good" does not mean you should hold a grudge against him.
That is more of a reason why you should be his friend, to make him good.
Tell your neighbour.
That "that woman is not good" does not mean you should hold a grudge.
That is more of a reason why you should be her friend, to change her.
Can you face your neighbour and say:
"That you are not good does not mean I should hold a grudge against you.
That is more of a reason I should be your friend to change you."
The SCOAN Sunday Service
So, where are we going?
Where are we going now? Can you see that you are not free of all this?
You are here today. You have so many enemies - uncountable ones.
You see them as the enemy.
No! They are not your enemies!
They are to build you, mould you and reform you.
Those you call enemies are to build you, mould you and reform you.
How? They will make you pray the more, fast the more.
Hm. Over to you.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
If someone makes you pray the more, is he your enemy?
If somebody makes you fast the more, you call him enemy?
The SCOAN Sunday Service
If not the attack of the past, you cannot be strong like this.
You are strong in the Lord because of attack.
You are strong in the Lord because of what people are saying about you.
But I have said:
Settle your conscience because your heart is the communication point, the contact point for God.
If God wants to come to you, it is through your heart.
If your heart is full of envy, jealousy, unforgiveness, pain of the past, bad feelings towards others,
where would God come?
Your altar is your heart. Your prayer room is in your heart.
If your prayer room is dirty, full of unforgiveness and pain, you don't have a prayer room.
The altar you have at home is just cosmetic.
My altar at home is cosmetic; the real altar is here.
Thy Kingdom come.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Thank you.
TT: Mel Flowers 15/07/2018
RV: J Margaret Fernandez 19/07/18